

+1 832-457-9872

andrey.sibiriakov@gmail.com

www.andrew-sib.com

in LinkedIn link

# **Summary**

Front-end developer with extensive experience in building **complex applications since 2019**. Interested in devising a better **problem-solving** method for challenging tasks. The basic aim is to achieve **the highest quality of delivered product**. An active participant in "Codewars", demonstrating a genuine passion for programming. **Enthusiastic** about expanding knowledge and mastering new concepts and new technologies.

# **Experience**

### **ChipAssist Switzerland**

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Apr. 2021 - Present

- Developed a marketplace utilizing React.js, Redux and TypeScript, that has grown up to 1000+ active users.
- The loading speed has been increased by five times through optimization and the splitting of lightweight chunks.
- Built a stock exchange platform **connecting 100+ sellers** around the world.
- Created a complex chat system allowing communication and purchase order processing.
- Designed and developed own admin panel for associates.
- Mentoring of junior specialists.
- Unit testing utilizing Jest and Behave, deployment to production

May 2020 - Apr. 2021

#### Freelance

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

- Developed **10+ dynamic websites and landing pages** utilizing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, resulting in a 25% increase in user engagement and a 15% boost in website conversions
- Creation of graphic and video content
- Designed and developed SPA applications
- Content management

### **Education**

IT-incubator Jan. 2020 - May 2021

REACT FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT COURSE WWW.IT-INCUBATOR.IO

**Moscow Technical University of Communications and Informatics** 

Sep. 2018 - Jul. 2022

BACHELOR'S DEGREE, COMPUTER SCIENCE

## **Skills**

**Programming:** JavaScript, TypeScript **Frameworks:** React.js, Redux, Next.js

Other technologies: REST API, Axios, Webpack, Docker, Git, Jest, Behave, Material UI, Tailwind, Bootstrap

**Languages:** • English - B1 (active learning)

• Russian - native speaker